degruyter.com 2016-10-12

# Privacy Statement

## Welcome to DE GRUYTER Publishers!

Thank you for visiting our website and for your interest in our company and our products. We take great care to ensure your privacy while visiting our website. Please note the following information regarding our privacy policy:

We do not assume any responsibility for the content of external links provided by other companies. We do not have any infl uence over the design and the contents of those websites. Since we can not controll how the provider of external links treat your private information, our privacy statement and our responsibility refers only to our own website. If you do have any question regarding the privacy statement of the companies in question, we would like to ask you to contact those companies directly.

The collecting, processing, and use of your data occurs within the framework provided by legal regulation. Please refer to <http://www.datenschutz.de/privo/> for an English version of this regulation. As personal or private data we consider any information you fill in in our forms, i.e. your email address, all information regarding ordering and billing, the postal address and the method of payment, as well as, all data provided by server protocolls. Personal data is only collected in as much it is required for the technical process. Personal information you provide us with (such as your name and postal address or email address) will be used by us for correspondence only or for the purposes for which you gave us the information. Occasionally, we may also use it to inform you of new services and products related to those you have ordered and of changes and new developments within De Gruyter Publishers. By purchasing our products online or registering for our products and services online, you agree to De Gruyter Publishers using your personal information in this way. Under no circumstances will we sell or forward your information for whatever reason to a third party.

In the following, we would like to provide you with details about the kind of information we gather during your visit to our website and how that information is being used:

###   
Server Protocolls

Walter de Gruyter GmbH gathers and saves in its server protocolls automatically all information provided by your browser. Th ese are in particular: The file and the URL you visit, the HTTP answering code, the type / version of the browser, the operating system, the previous visited URL, the host name of the computer used (IP address or Domain name), date and time of the visit, as well as the amount of bytes being transfreed during your visit.

At Walter de Gruyter Publishers, this information can not be connected to a particular individual. Th is information is not merged with any information gathered through other sources.

###   
Shop

Our online shop is based on a secure HTTPS-connection (SSL); your data is being encoded before it is transferred. When you use our online shop, we ask our customers to provide us with certain personal details, such as your email address, your name, postal address, and your account information. On the shop pages you will be able to see which data is necessary to process your order and which information is optional. We need and use this information solely for processing your order.

###   
Cookies

This website uses etracker technology ([www.etracker.com](http://www.etracker.com/)) to collect visitor behavior data. This data is collected anonymously to be used for marketing and optimization purposes. All visitor data is saved using an anonymous user ID and can be aggregated to a usage profile. Cookies may be used to collect and save this data, but the data remains strictly anonymous. The data will not be used to identify a visitor personally and are not aggregated with any personal data. The collection and storage of data may be [refused](https://www.etracker.de/privacy?et=EsbJNm) at any time with respect to subsequent services.

In order to use our site, you will need to set the option in your browser to accept cookies. Unfortunately, there is no way to program a shopping basket that retains the items you put into it without using cookies. We do not use permanent cookies. Once you close your browser, the cookie will be deleted automatically. The cookies are only used to keep track of the items you place in the shopping basket - we do not track or retain your personal information beyond what is needed to complete the order. A cookie is a simple piece of text. It is not a program, or a plug-in. It cannot be used as a virus, and it cannot access your hard drive.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States .

In case IP-anonymisation is activated on this website, your IP address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transfered to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymisation is active on this website.

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to website activity and internet usage.

The IP-address, that your Browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics, will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Addon for your current web browser: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

As an alternative to the browser Addon or within browsers on mobile devices, you can click this link in order to opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics within this website in the future (the opt-out applies only for the browser in which you set it and within this domain). An opt-out cookie will be stored on your device, which means that you'll have to click this link again, if you delete your cookies.

###   
Newsletter

If you would like to receive our electronic newsletter, we need your current email address as well as the means to establish that you are the owner of that email address or that the owner of the email address agrees to receive the newsletter. No further information is required. You can withdraw your consent to the saving of the data, the email address, and its use to send the newsletter at any time.

###   
Information policy / Deleting of personal data

Your trust is important to us. Therefore, we are prepared to answer any question you might have in regard to your personal data gathered by our company at any time. If you have any question which has not been addressed by the declaration of our privacy policy or if you would like to ask us to delete your personal information, please contact us directly at: 

Walter de Gruyter GmbH  
Genthiner Strasse 13  
D-10785 Berlin / Germany  
Tel: +49 30 260 05-0  
Fax: +49 30 260 05-251  
E-mail: service [ at ] degruyter.com

###   
Data Security Officer

Thorsten Feldmann  
e-mail: [datenschutz@degruyter.com](mailto:datenschutz@degruyter.com)
